<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Marín's - Blog</title><link>https://marinhero.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Marín's - Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://marinhero.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Calculate your One Rep Max Easily using Deno, Denoflare and iOS Shortcuts</title><link>https://marinhero.com/posts/rpe-max/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marinhero.com/posts/rpe-max/</guid><description>What is this? This is a program that automates the process we follow at my gym to calculate the weight we should lift in our sets based on our RPE, one rep max, and set count.
What is RPE? RPE stands for Rate of Perceived Exertion. It is a subjective measure used to gauge the intensity of exercise or physical activity, based on an individual&amp;rsquo;s personal perception of how hard they feel they are working.</description></item><item><title>Do’s and don’ts for a successful SDE internship</title><link>https://marinhero.com/posts/segment-internship/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marinhero.com/posts/segment-internship/</guid><description>Last summer, I had the opportunity to mentor an intern at Twilio Segment. This was a first for me and I really enjoyed it. The experience opened a new avenenue for my career that I want to keep exploring.
By the end of the internship, Kevin (the intern) and I co-wrote a blogpost with some of our learnings and titled it do’s and don’ts for a successful SDE internship go check it out!</description></item><item><title>Tetris, in TypeScript</title><link>https://marinhero.com/posts/typescript-tetris/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marinhero.com/posts/typescript-tetris/</guid><description>With the intention of getting more familiarized with TypeScript, I decided to start a new project. It&amp;rsquo;s been many years since the last time I made a game from scrath so it seemed fitting to give that a go. I chose Tetris because it&amp;rsquo;s a well known game, with a defined set of problems and functionality. All I had to worry about was to code their solutions.
The TypeScript Lesson I did get more familiar with TypeScript, some of its strengths, caveats and tooling.</description></item><item><title>Never Lose Another Bash Command Ever Again!</title><link>https://marinhero.com/posts/bash-history/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marinhero.com/posts/bash-history/</guid><description>Every once in awhile, I would find a Bash shell command that gets me out of a big problem. After hours of troubleshooting, I would find THE command, run it, and then I would move on and forget about that command. The next time I faced the same issue, I might remember the command, but if not I would try to get it from my Bash history using the command:$&amp;gt; history.</description></item><item><title>x86, x64, ARM? I Just Want to Download my Program!</title><link>https://marinhero.com/posts/architectures/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marinhero.com/posts/architectures/</guid><description>More often than not, when I go to a website to download a program I find a screen like this.
These are some of the questions that come to my mind.
Why are there so many options? Why don&amp;rsquo;t we just create one universal binary format so we don&amp;rsquo;t have to decide this? Aren&amp;rsquo;t computers supposed to just speak in zeroes and ones? What happens if I download the wrong binary?</description></item><item><title>Ports and Port Scanners</title><link>https://marinhero.com/posts/port-scanning/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://marinhero.com/posts/port-scanning/</guid><description>Have you ever wondered how an attacker knows which services to target? How can they determine which exploit they should use? port scanning is what gives the initial pieces of intel to them. It’s part of the process known as fingerprinting that will determine what in a system has the potential to be exploited. Let me tell you a story about what’s possible with this information:
In April 2017, The Shadow Brokers leaked an exploit developed by the NSA named EternalBlue.</description></item></channel></rss>